Justin Traglia: Oh, hey, sorry, I didn't realize this call even started.
Justin Traglia: Or the meeting room.
Jihoon: Hey, no worries.
Jihoon: How's it going?
Justin Traglia: It's going well, just waking up.
Justin Traglia: I'm reviewing, bug bounty submissions.
Justin Traglia: How about you?
Jihoon: Nice close.
Jihoon: Yeah, I was just preparing for this breakout.
Jihoon: Looking into EIP stuff… Ava?
Justin Traglia: Yeah, Evan.
Iván | ethrex: It.
Justin Traglia: Any success in, The thing that you mentioned to me yesterday.
Justin Traglia: Jayhan.
Jihoon: Oh, yeah.
Jihoon: Successful. Yep.
Justin Traglia: Great to hear.
Jihoon: Hello, Mehdi. Hello, Christian.
Mehdi Aouadi: Well, guys.
Cristian Conache: Hello, everyone.
Jihoon: you All right, let's get started.
Jihoon: Hello, everyone. Welcome to FOCIL Breakout 43.
Jihoon: We're close to lunch, FOCIL devnet Zero, so shall we start with client updates?
Iván | ethrex: I can start.
Jihoon: Go ahead.
Iván | ethrex: okay, on our side, we've been updating the…
Iván | ethrex: The branch with the latest spec tests.
Iván | ethrex: I saw that my PRs fixing stuff on the execution spec side were merged.
Iván | ethrex: And… All that was,
Iván | ethrex: Left was releasing a new version, including those fixes, so now it should be fine. I just checked Hive, and we are failing 3 tests, so now I'm focusing on making them pass, but we should be… we should be good by… in a couple of hours.
Jihoon: Do we need another release after 030 release?
Iván | ethrex: No, no, the 0.3 release is good. We are just failing 3 tests that I'm working on them right now.
Jihoon: Okay, cool. Thank you.
NC: For Lodestar, we have also replaced the FOCIL branch on top of the beta.2 release.
NC: And, we have also hooked up, with the… Gossip validation spec tests, and, they're all passing.
Jihoon: Great to hear. Thank you, Asif.
Jihoon: Has survey odd passing.
Jihoon: Any other clients?
Mehdi Aouadi: Yeah, I can give an update for Teku. This morning I fixed the two issues raised by EthPandaOps.
Mehdi Aouadi: And while doing that, I discovered another issue I'm fixing.
Mehdi Aouadi: Hopefully, just after the call, I would publish a new docker image for devnet 0, and we would be ready.
Marc: On Nethermind side, not too much to update. We're, ready for the DevNet. Just, like, work on a few small fixes and think a bit about the, FOCIL and frames interaction.
Cristian Conache: On the Lighthouse side, we're also pretty close to having a DevNet Zero-ready branch, including our work so far. We're still working through some small things on the gossip verification side and new payload v6 request.
Cristian Conache: So we have to… we hope to have a branch ready maybe this week.
Fabio Di Fabio: Yeah, on Besu side, the…
Fabio Di Fabio: We are ready for the DevNet. I need to review some IV tests that are still failing.
Jihoon: So it seems like… Both ELs are failing some tests, but…
Jihoon: Are we okay with going with 7 to 0 as is?
Jihoon: Or do we have to fix it?
Jihoon: Should be good.
Fabio Di Fabio: No. I think we we should go.
Jihoon: Okay, cool. Thank you.
Jihoon: And… If DevNet Zero is ready for Lighthouse, please share in the chat.
Jihoon: Cristian, I mean, at 8RND.
Jihoon: So we can add it.
Cristian Conache: Sure, I'll share once it's ready.
Jihoon: Okay, cool. Thank you.
Jihoon: Alright, thanks for sharing the updates.
Jihoon: Let's move on to spec updates.
Jihoon: Do you want to discuss Beacon APIs?
Jihoon: Nancy or Nico.
NC: There's really not much… I think Nico, brought up that, we should… refrain from merging
NC: the hazy Beacon API spec.
NC: For now.
NC: Because they're still, trying to merge all the Glamsterdam Beacon APIs into the current release… into the next release.
NC: Before we start, merging the FOCILs.
NC: Regarding the Beacon API spec, there's really not much change in terms of, endpoints.
NC: But I think Nico also, caught
NC: an oversight, which is the inclusion list bits. We forgot to include that into the payload attributes event stream.
NC: Which Lodestar currently doesn't implement that.
NC: Other than that, there's not much.
Jihoon: How are other clients doing with Beacon APIs?
Jihoon: Did Teku and Lighthouse also implement Beacon APIs?
Mehdi Aouadi: I believe we have… we've implemented most of them. I need to double check, to be honest.
Mehdi Aouadi: But yeah, I think for Teku they're already implemented, yeah.
Cristian Conache: Same on Lighthouse side. They should be implemented.
NC: What about event stream?
Cristian Conache: I will have to check that.
Cristian Conache: Not really sure yet.
Mehdi Aouadi: For Teku, we have the including the SD-VIN stream. I need to check if… There are still other missing.
Jihoon: Cool.
Jihoon: Do we have… Any other stuff to discuss?
Iván | ethrex: This is not regarding, the Beacon API specs, but regarding the FOCIL class frames specs.
Iván | ethrex: We are almost done with them.
Iván | ethrex: should be done by tomorrow, or later in this week, but it should be good to present them in the frames breakout, if it's okay. I will do it in the next breakout of FOCIL, but
Iván | ethrex: Probably birth sooner, to do it soon.
Jihoon: Great, this.
Jihoon: Very nice to hear.
Jihoon: FOSSIL Breakout is in next week, right?
Iván | ethrex: Oh, I thought it was in a couple of weeks, not sure.
Iván | ethrex: FOCIL Breakout in two weeks, but the Frames one in next week.
Jihoon: Next week, yeah.
Jihoon: Okay, cool.
Jihoon: Just to confirm, that's… We were talking about execution specs, right? Not consensus specs.
Iván | ethrex: Yeah.
Jihoon: Okay.
Jihoon: Circling back to… the engine API stuff, sorry, Beacon API stuff, before touching FOSSIL Change with frames.
Jihoon: Yeah, I believe this is the right PR that… We're talking about… Excellent. Oh, yeah.
Jihoon: Eduardo, do you wanna… do you have something in mind to present?
Jihoon: About the change?
Iván | ethrex: Sorry, that was for me.
Jihoon: No, I was asking.
Jihoon: Tuma, because he asked me in the chat.
Iván | ethrex: Okay.
Jihoon: Maybe worth, yeah, sorry, maybe worth presenting what would change.
Jihoon: Straight put mechanism for index-based mechanism.
Jihoon: Yeah, we can… discuss what to change on the CL side.
Jihoon: In the next possible breakout.
Jihoon: I'm.
Jihoon: Index-based mechanism, yeah.
Jihoon: Yeah, that sounds great. So,
Jihoon: Either you or I can prepare something so that people can be aware of.
Jihoon: What will be changed?
Jihoon: on the CL to support the interaction between FOCIL and frames.
Jihoon: And, yeah, we can… have that…
Jihoon: And the agenda for the next breakout.
Jihoon: The chat just didn't ask.
Jihoon: When do you want to include simple CFI features into FOCIL specs?
Jihoon: Like, EIP8015… We are… Gonna work on another EIP
Jihoon: It's by Mac… it's by NC.
Jihoon: Nice.
Jihoon: It's 8365 without the exit feature.
Jihoon: So… Definitely, they were not gonna make it to DEFNET 0, but… When do we feel about…
Jihoon: adding them into devnet cycle.
Jihoon: Or… Do we need to bring that up to like ACDT seal breakout?
NC: I think it's… I think it's still too early to tell.
NC: I think that depends on… I don't know, the outcome of DevNet Zero, I guess.
Jihoon: Yeah, makes sense.
Jihoon: Okay.
Justin Traglia: Yeah, I mean…
Jihoon: or.
Justin Traglia: We should wait.
Jihoon: Yeah, go ahead.
Justin Traglia: After DevNet Zero.
Justin Traglia: But I was just getting, like, rough… Feelings for this.
Justin Traglia: And Tamar, I think it. We can't SFI something until it's been included in a devnet. So
Justin Traglia: If my understanding is correct.
Jihoon: Yeah, that's my understanding, too. I think we need to put things into DevNet once it's CFI, and if it's stabilized and making good progress, then we can consider CFI-ing them.
Justin Traglia: Yeah. I, I would advocate to include them as soon as possible.
Justin Traglia: So probably DevNet 1 or DevNet 2, if possible.
Jihoon: Yeah, so… We can open PRs, adding those CFI features.
Jihoon: Like, 8015, 8365.
Jihoon: And… Based on the result of DEVNet0, we can decide to include which of them, and in which cycle.
NC: I also realized that, Barnabas is pushing, to get a devnet up for shorter slots.
NC: Which, is on top of HESI.
NC: I don't know, like, how… with that.
NC: would the timeline be depending on also DevNet Zero, or is it something, that's running parallel?
Jihoon: Yeah, it's not… CFI.
Jihoon: Yeah, so… Not sure what we can decide on.
Jihoon: Quick slots, definite timing.
Justin Traglia: Yeah, I mean, he is pushing for that. I wouldn't worry too much about it right now. But yeah, you're right, it does depend on HESI.
Justin Traglia: I wouldn't.
Justin Traglia: Suggest launching or trying to do anything before the first, as he also does not.
Jihoon: Yeah, I think we can, for now, focus on launching FOSSIL WN0 and this week we're going to have ACDC so we can see
Jihoon: Which EIPs will gonna get CFI more, and… Yeah, we can… Start from there.
Jihoon: Actually, that's all the agenda that I prepared for today.
Jihoon: Do we have anything?
Jihoon: More to discuss, or any questions or comments?
Jihoon: We can go ahead and wrap up this call, so…
Jihoon: Two weeks from now, we can discuss…
Jihoon: Brains and FOCIL interaction, and the necessary changes.
Jihoon: on the CL and EL, and probably we're gonna discuss more before DEF CON, so… Yeah.
Jihoon: Thank you guys for joining, and… Theorem 2x.
Justin Traglia: Thanks, Jayhan.
NC: just.
Justin Traglia: Bye, everyone.
NC: Thank you.
Fabio Di Fabio: Thank you. Bye.
Jihoon: Thank you. Bye-bye.
Cristian Conache: Thank you.